

borboleta@gmail.com

Toronto, ON, Canada

### **PROFILE**

I provide meaning and context to data so that people can prioritize and make informed decisions that lead to quantifiable results. Working as a Data Scientist for over ten years, I've collaborated with Product and Marketing teams in B2B and B2C companies, supporting the team to achieve their goals.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# STAFF PRODUCT DATA SCIENTIST, MOZILLA – 2022-PRESENT

I work on the user engagement team for the Firefox mobile apps. The role includes deep dive analyses of opportunities and new features, partnering with PMs and engineers for the planning and execution of experiments, defining methodologies and measurement strategies to promote learning from Marketing campaigns, and mentoring other data scientists working on our products.

# STAFF DATA SCIENTIST, SHOPIFY - 2020-2022

My main role was to collaborate with our Theme Store and App Store teams. I defined key metrics appropriate for each project, created data models to support our reports and exploratory analyses, implemented a tracking strategy to better understand how users interacted with our product, executed experiments, built dashboards, and helped uncover data insights. In addition, as a technical lead, I contributed to initiatives to improve how Data Science teams operate across the organization: I had been championing data discovery projects and documentation since 2017, running workshops to teach SQL, and defining best practices and standards for how we communicate with data.

# DATA SCIENCE LEAD, SHOPIFY - 2012-2019

I built the foundations for Marketing data at Shopify, supporting the growth of the company from 20k merchants to over 800k. My role involved balancing the technical requirements of building and maintaining new data models, as part of a company wide effort to build a new data warehouse in advance of our IPO, with the demands from stakeholders whose decisions were supported by data analyses. From a technical standpoint, the work of my team involved instrumenting data collection through Kafka events, extracting data from external APIs, building data models using PySpark, and creating reports in Tableau and Mode Analytics.

In July/2017, I transitioned to a technical lead role to focus on improving the Data Science discipline across several teams. I helped identify and prioritize our main challenges, define standards, share the knowledge between teams, and create tools to optimize how we worked.

### MARKETING INTELLIGENCE MANAGER, DAFITI - 2010-2012

At Dafiti I led the team that provided analytics support to the company's Marketing efforts. I helped the company go from launch to largest fashion ecommerce in Latin America in less than two years. I was responsible for defining the strategy to measure Marketing campaigns and customer behavior, from the tools and tracking code implemented on the site to the URL parameters used by each channel, ensuring the consistency and reliability of the data collected. I analyzed and reported on Marketing campaigns across multiple channels, consolidating data from internal and external sources to optimize the results.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, BUSCAPÉ - 2010

Development of new features for a comparison shopping website using Java.

SYSTEM ANALYST, UOL - 2009

Development of the billing platform using Java.

LEAD MOBILE PROGRAMMER, DEVWORKS - 2004

Development of games for mobile phones using Java.

SYSTEM ANALYST, ACCENTURE - 2000-2003

Consulting projects for several clients using a variety of technologies.

#### **EDUCATION**

Ms. Computer Science — Universidade de São Paulo, 2011

Bs. Computational and Applied Mathematics — Universidade de São Paulo, 2006

Ba. Business Administration — Fundação Getúlio Vargas, 2001

# Online Courses

University of British Columbia

Measuring Marketing Campaigns Online, July 2011 Creating and Managing the Analytical Business Culture, October 2011

Coursera

Data Engineering with Google Cloud Specialization, March 2020 Computing for Data Analysis, November 2013 Introduction to Data Science, June 2013 Model Thinking, May 2013 Web Intelligence and Big Data, December 2012

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

SQL (BigQuery, Presto, Redshift, Vertica)
Data Warehousing (Dimensional Modeling)
Data visualization and reporting (Tableau, Looker, Mode, Redash)
Python (Jupyter, Pandas, PySpark)
Google Cloud and Google APIs
HTML, CSS and JavaScript